Contact

nan.librado@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nan-ybarra-dnp-mba-rn-nea-bc-5472048a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Patient Safety Leadership Healthcare Management

Languages

English

Certifications

Nurse Executive - Advance Board Certified

Honors-Awards

Mastery in Excellence- MBA Capstone

Good Samaritan Bronze Winner Leadership

Publications

Hurricane Harvey: One Hospital's Journey Toward Organizational Resilience

Nan Ybarra, DNP, MBA, RN, NEA-BC

Nursing Executive

Greater Seattle Area

Summary

Experienced healthcare executive leading services across multiple campuses. Dedicated to improving Obstetrical and Neonatal outcomes. Strengths include: strengthening quality programs, mentoring leaders, financial stewardship, driving and sustaining change and operationalizing innovative roles and workflows.

Under Dr. Ybarra's leadership hospitals have experienced an increase in patient census, decrease in severe maternal morbidity, expansion of service lines and increase in revenue capture as well as NPR favorable to budget and favorable operating income to budget.

Dr. Ybarra's commitment to empowering others is a tenant which guides all interactions, behaviors and work. Fortunate to have experience and success in building and leading high functioning teams whose expertise and accomplishments are championed, promoted, and highlighted. A leader whose work to empower others, facilitate collaboration, and promote professional growth, results in a high level of satisfaction, professional development, and system visibility for team members.

Dr. Ybarra is a 2015 University of San Francisco graduate of the Doctor of Nursing Practice Executive Leadership program and Antioch University PhD Student in the Graduate School of Leadership and Change.

Experience

UW Medicine Nursing Executive February 2020 - Present (6 months) Texas Children's Hospital Pavilion for Women Director of Inpatient Services June 2012 - February 2020 (7 years 9 months) Houston, Texas

Provide leadership for all inpatient units within Texas Children's Pavilion for Women campus: including Labor & Delivery, Triage, Mother Baby Unit, Well Infant Nursery, Antepartum Unit, OB Critical Care Unit, OB Perioperative Services, Maternal Transport, Women's Services Float Pool.

Leadership and oversight of 144 beds and >375 FTEs. Large academic setting with > 6000 deliveries annually, Budgetary planning and fiscal oversight and responsibility of > \$40 million operational budget.

Houston Methodist San Jacinto Nurse Manager Maternal Child June 2007 - July 2012 (5 years 2 months)

Nurse Manager Maternal Child, Level II NICU and Well Baby Nursery; Interim Nurse Manager Pediatric, Ortho-Joint and Medical Surgical Unit

Management and leadership of > 150 FTEs and oversight of 62 beds in academic setting. Responsible for quality outcomes, financial stewardship, financial reports with productivity and salary dollar variances.

Education

Antioch University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Leadership & Change · (2017 - 2022)

University of San Francisco

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Executive Leadership (2015)

Western Governors University

Master of Business Administration, MBA - Healthcare Management · (2013)

The University of Texas Medical Branch

Bachelor of Science, Nursing (1995)